# **Tony Fan**

## **Product Designer**

Data-driven product and visual designer with over 7 years of experience. Led the redesign of the company website, revamped mobile apps, improved application usability, and conducted comprehensive user research, resulting in a 28% increase in customer satisfaction by identifying new feature opportunities.

#### tonyfan.com

☐ 639-916-1781

in LinkedIn

# **Work Experience**

#### UX UI / Visual Designer | STEER Technologies

March 2023 - April 2024 (Toronto, ON, Canada)

- Led to redesigned the onboarding, login, and order system pages for an e-commerce mobile app, resulting in a 28% increase in conversion rates and a 25% enhancement in user engagement.
- Established a design system including UI Components, Patterns and collaborate with frond end developers that improved the work efficiency of both the design and development by 45%.
- Conduct prototype usability test with cross-functional team and users to refine user experience before the product is full developed.
- Built responsive official website with Web-flow and HTML/CSS/ JavaScript that effectively increased brand awareness 26%.
- Created Brand identity guideline (Logo, Color Palette, Typography, Images) to ensures consistent and professional brand representation across all platforms, enhancing recognition, trust, and efficiency.

## UX UI / Visual Designer | OTT Financial Group

Jun 2021 - December 2022 (Toronto, ON, Canada)

- Led to redesign fintech mobile app onboarding screen, usable interface, design system, signup and remittance process based on usability test and feedback for users to seamlessly make remittance. Decreasing monthly churn rate from 45% to 15%.
- Managed to optimize mobile app navigation bar icons, purchase/ payment pages and adding filter function to make product more user-friendly and easily find content through user research.
   Increasing conversion rate from 3% to 12%.
- Created a responsive SaaS(PREKA) website using Web-flow and HTML/CSS/Javascript. Increasing a product's exposure by 45%.
- Edit promotional video with After effect and Premier Pro for new product launch.

# Graphic / Ul Designer | Evergrande Group

Jan 2015 - Jun 2018 (Shaoxing, China)

- Created a brand guideline for real estate project including logo, color palette, typography, tagline and patterns. Improving project awareness and exposure on social media.
- Designed flyers, posters, website landing pages, mobile promotion pages, social media graphics and videos for weekly activity.
   Increasing traffic which client visit real estate sales center by 30%.

#### **Education**

#### Sheridan College

Postgraduate Degree in Interactive Media
Management, GPA 3.94

Sep 2020 - April 2021

#### Certification

## Google

Google UX Design Certificate

#### Skills

User Research
Affinity Diagram
Information Architecture
User Flows
Sketching / Wireframing
Usability testing
Prototyping
Illustration
Motion Design
Brand Design
Video editting
HTML/CSS/JavaScript
Problem solving mindset
Strong communication

#### **Tools**

Strong storytelling

Team player

Figma

Adobe XD

Protopie

Photoshop

Illustrator

**After Effects** 

Premiere Pro

Webflow

Wordpress